

DATA SCIENTIST · A.I. DEVELOPER

251 Platt's Lane Apt. 619, London, ON, CA N6H 4P4

□ (+1) 519-520-0625 | **□** junaedcse@gmail.com | **□** junaedcse | **□** junaedcse

"Background in Computer Science"

Summary

Expert Data Scientist and Developer with long, strong background in Computer Science. Extensive experience creating real world applications and open source projects. Expert on several frameworks, including TensorFlow, Keras, Theano, scikit-learn and PyTorch. Extremely passionate about programming, deep learning, and deep reinforcement learning.

Education

University of Western Ontario

PHD CANDIDATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Kingston University

M.PHIL IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Hogskolan Dalarna University

M.Sc. in Computer Engineering

Ahsanullah University

B.Sc in Computer Engineering

London, Canada Current London, England

Borlange, Sweden

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Experience _

Densyfy Inc.

London, ON

Al Developer August 2017 - Current

- Building a machine learning infrastructure for densified video processing based on computer vision, speech, audio, cyber physical systems, etc.
- · Leading a team for developing an inhouse data center for creating specific dataset for specific purpose.
- Design and develop different machine learning systems, insights, and algorithms, and then prototype, deploy to production, and test them to ensure all client's business needs are covered.
- Developing a framework for validating the solution and manage overall software implementation lifecycles of projects, ensuring compliance with existing and future enterprise implementation standards.
- Optimizing algorithms and prototyping solutions for efficient implementation. Extending prototypes into fully functional, polished solutions ready for internal and/or external use. Supporting projects with thorough documentation of usage, design decisions and capabilities.
- Integration of voice recognition system for speaker diarization. Extensively worked with latest soa deep speech learning platform like DeepSpeech.

Western University

London, ON

RESEARCHER, ROADLAB

August 2013 - Current

- Working as a researcher in RoadLab which aims to understand the driver's intent for the automated vehicle framework.(Linux, C++)
- Developed softwares for maneuver prediction based on driver's intent. The data acquired from an instrumented vehicle loaded with on board diagnostic tools and stereo cameras.
- Exhaustively applied deep learning frameworks for on road significant object detection.
- Developing a framework for on road traffic event recognition and integrate it with iADAS prediction framework.
- Optimizing algorithms and prototyping solutions for efficient implementation.

RESEARCHER, DIRC LAB

- Embedded software development for cell phones, testing and performance evaluation of surveillance video analysis using C++ and web application using Java script.
- Designed experiments in the cluster for better processing in Linux OS using Eclipse.
- Developed an algorithm to evaluate the performance of the combination of local features of tracking objects for LG Electronics, Korea (Eclipse, Java, SVM).
- Designed and developed tools for detection and tracking articulate human motion in unconstrained scenarios using a single surveillance camera (C++, Boost, MATLAB, SVM).
- Designed and developed tools to track silhouettes in videos to solve nonlinear articulated pedestrian tracking problem (C++, Boost, MATLAB, SVM).

Multimode Group, Microsoft Division

Dhaka, Bangladesh

ASSISTANT MANAGER (I.T.)

January 2004 - January 2007

- Worked as an Assistant System Manager, responsible for providing software solutions for more than 500 employees. It was a team of 8 people providing embedded technical solutions inside the group of companies.
- I was responsible to provide technical solutions using Microsoft products. For the software development I had implemented the ERP software in C++ and SQL Server. I have planned, designed the information system of the company and implemented. I was involved in upgrading the software by adding new features and maintained it for two years in a resource constrained environment.
- Actively participated in UI design, feature development and conceptualization.
- I was in charge of the communication with the clients, arranged workshops to share views.
- Involved in web based software quality testing and responsible for making marketing policies, improving the business areas for Microsoft products.
- · Have experience in working with full project life cycle, specially designing, developing and support phase.

Areas of Interest ____

Deep Learning/Neural Networks, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Mathematical Modelling, Big Data Analysis, Network Analysis, AI Platform bulding, Distributed and Embedded Systems

Programming Tools ____

Programming Languages Python: 6+ years, Matlab: 8+ years, C++: 10+ years, JavaScript: 1+ years, Dart: 1+ years, C, Java, Prolog, Lisp, SQL, XML

Tools/Frameworks _____

Data Science: Tensorflow (python), Scikit Learn (python), Keras, Numpy, NetworkX (python), Theano PvTorch

Development: Git, QT, Visual Studio Team Repository (c,c++), PostgreSQL

Leadership and Teamwork _____

- Leaded a group of people to keep the flow of Microsoft products supply chain management in order.
- Organized a workshop in Multimode Group, Microsoft Division.
- Worked as a researcher in a team assisted on Software development and performance evaluation.
- Worked for Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology Alumni Association.

Reference ____

Available upon request.